PAVAN K RAO

GAME DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a passionate game programmer with 5 years of experience in developing games for mobile and PC in Unity. I am currently looking for opportunities to create impressive games and learn from some of the industry's seasoned veterans. Some of my favorite games are from the Castelvania, Darksouls, and DevilMayCry series.

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

Unity

C#

CONTACT INFORMATION

Phone: +91 7624853821
Email: raopavank@gmail.com

Address: BTM Layout, Bengaluru, Karnataka

560076. India

Portfolio: <u>compilingdreamsgames.wordpress.com</u>

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Associate Game Developer

JumpStart Games | Bangalore (JAN 2018 - DEC 2019)

- Worked closely with art and design teams to develop features for Neopets: Legends and Letter.
- Worked on bug fixes and maintenance of various projects such as World Of Jumpstart, Math Blaster HyperBlast 2 HD, and Neopets: Ghoul Catchers.

Game Developer

Moonfrog Labs. | Bangalore (JAN 2020 - Nov 2022)

- Ported the Ludo Club game from cocos2dx to Unity3D.
- Took part in live ops support and bug fixes for Ludo Club.
- Implemented several features such as achievements and collectibles on both the server(nodeJS) and the client-side(C#).
- Deployed and monitored server release on the production environment.
- Worked on adding functionality to admin tools and developer tools.

EDUCATION

Bharathiar University

B.Sc(Hons) in Game Development | 2014 - 2017

Mahesh PUC

Intermediate (+2) 2012 - 2014

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Lan Wars: An online top-down multiplayer shooter (Unity)

- Implemented a peer-to-peer / server-client-based online multiplayer in Unity/C# using Unity Networking for PC.
- Handled adding animation and syncing it with character movements and actions.

Hide in Hide: Single-tap-based rhythm game for Android.

 Developed the core mechanics of syncing enemy actions with thr BPM of background music in Unity.

C++ Render Engine: C++ render engine using OpenGl

Developed a component based render engine in C++ and OpenGI
, supports loading of 3d models, blin-phong lighting, deferred
rendering and GUI,